George Curtis Waldo Journals MS118
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
George Curtis Waldo Journals
1851 -- 1857
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Waldo, George Curtis
MS118
0.25 Linear Feet
113 Digital Object(s)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Biographical / Historical
George Curtis Waldo was born on March 20, 1837 in Lynn, Essex Co., Massachusetts as the son of Josiah Crosby Waldo and Elmira Ruth Ballou. His mother was the daughter of Rev. Hosea Ballou, great-uncle of Hosea Ballou 2d, who served as first president of Tufts College. George Curtis Waldo was a student at Tufts College in its first few years, graduated from Tufts A1860 and G1860, and then received an honorary degree of Doctor of Literature in 1900.
He enlisted in Company E, 2nd Infantry Regiment Connecticut and then mustered out within a few months in the summer of 1861, due to ailing health. Given his health he stopped his study of law at the office of the A. C. Lippit in New London Connecticut and began working for the Bridgeport Standard in 1867. He became the chief editor of the 'Standard,' a daily and weekly newspaper published in Bridgeport, Ct. in 1888. He was a junior warden of the Christ Episcopal Church and a co-founder and then secretary of the Bridgeport Scientific Society, and vice-president of the Fairfield County Historical Society which later joined with the Scientific Society. Besides serving on the Bridgeport board of education, he was also member of several of its committees; he was president and vice-president of the old Eclectic club, and member of numerous other organizations including officer of the Republican Club of Bridgeport. He also served as shell fish commissioner of the state of Connecticut.
He married Annie Frye (great-great-granddaughter of Colonel James Frye commanding a regiment at Bunker Hill) in 1874 and they had three sons and one daughter. Waldo died in 1921.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains George C. Waldo's personal journals from 1851-57. Journal entries from August 1856 - January 1857 describe his first semester as a student at Tufts.
Alumni collections; University history; Tufts University -- History
- Journals, 1851 -- 1857; MS118.001; 0.25 Linear Feet; 113 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains George C. Waldo's personal journals from 1851-57. Journal entries from August 1856 - January 1857 describe his first semester as a student at Tufts.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged as found.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Journals, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001; Waldo, George Curtis (Box 1)
    - Journal, cover, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00001 (Box 1)
      page; Waldo, George Curtis
    - Journal, inside cover, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00002 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 1, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00003 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 2, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00004 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 3, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00005 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 4, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00006 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 5, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00007 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 6, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00008 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 7, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00009 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 8, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00010 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 9, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00011 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 10, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00012 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 11, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00013 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 12, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00014 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 13, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00015 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 14, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00016 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 15, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00017 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 16, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00018 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 17, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00019 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 18, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00020 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 19, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00021 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 20, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00022 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 21, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00023 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 22, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00024 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 23, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00025 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 24, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00026 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 25, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00027 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 26, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00028 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 27, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00029 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 28, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00030 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 29, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00031 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 30, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00032 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 31, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00033 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 32, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00034 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 33, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00035 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 34, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00036 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 35, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00037 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 36, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00038 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 37, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00039 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 38, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00040 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 41, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00041 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 42, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00042 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 43, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00043 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 44, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00044 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 45, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00045 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 46, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00046 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 47, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00047 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 48, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00048 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 49, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00049 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 50, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00050 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 51, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00051 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 52, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00052 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 53, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00053 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 62, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00054 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 63, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00055 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 64, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00056 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 65, 1851 -- 1854; MS118.001.001.00001.00057 (Box 1)
  - Journals, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002; Waldo, George Curtis (Box 1)
    Waldo, George Curtis
    - Journal, cover, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00001 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 1, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00002 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 2, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00003 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 3, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00004 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 4, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00005 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 5, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00006 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 6, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00007 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 7, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00008 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 8, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00009 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 9, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00010 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 10, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00011 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 11, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00012 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 12, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00013 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 13, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00014 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 14, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00015 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 15, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00016 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 16, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00017 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 17, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00018 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 18, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00019 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 19, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00020 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 20, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00021 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 21, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00022 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 22, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00023 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 23, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00024 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 24, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00025 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 25, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00026 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 26, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00027 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 27, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00028 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 28, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00029 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 29, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00030 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 30, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00031 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 31, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00032 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 32, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00033 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 33, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00034 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 34, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00035 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 35, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00036 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 36, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00037 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 37, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00038 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 38, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00039 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 39, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00040 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 40, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00041 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 41, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00042 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 42, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00043 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 43, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00044 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 44, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00045 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 45, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00046 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 46, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00047 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 47, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00048 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 48, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00049 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 49, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00050 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 50, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00051 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 51, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00052 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 52, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00053 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 53, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00054 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 54, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00055 (Box 1)
    - Journal, page 55, 1856 -- 1857; MS118.001.001.00002.00056 (Box 1)